准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
小小马戏团
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
动画总监
联合监制
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
看它们翻滚
See them flip
看它们翱翔
See them soar
看它们杂耍  还有更多花样
see them juggle and so much more
这里是海跳蚤马戏团
It's Circus Sea Fleas
它们生来就要让你快快乐乐
And they were born to please you
我们爱你  海跳蚤马戏团
We love you, Circus Sea Fleas
跳蚤们也爱你
And the fleas love you
记住  海跳蚤马戏团生来只为你演出
Remember, Circus Sea Fleas live to perform just for you
我们打心里十分认可
We've been emotionally validated
海跳蚤马戏团
马上订购你专属的海跳蚤马戏团吧
Send for your very own Circus Sea Fleas today
马上订购
我昨天就订了  还在等着呢
I sent for mine yesterday, and I'm still waiting
真倒霉啊
Bummer, dude
什么
What?
真倒霉啊
倒霉哥手办
Bummer Dude action figures
痛苦无比
They're miserable
倒霉哥手办
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
今天有一堆好东西要给你
Got a buncha great stuff for you today
邮件
全新一册锅铲商城目录
The new "Spatula Emporium" catalog
锅铲
不是这
No
你中彩得到的奖金
Free money from the sweepstakes you won
海绵宝宝
一百万
不是这
No
你家里人寄来的信
A letter from your family
不是这
No
包裹  有没有包裹
Packages, how about packages?
有没有寄给我的包裹
You have any packages for me?
没有包裹
No packages
抱歉让你失望了  海绵宝宝
Sorry to disappoint you, SpongeBob
你从哪看出来我失望的
What makes you think I'm disappointed?
一切都很好
Everything's just fine
好难过的海绵
Man, what a sad sponge
难过海绵
没错  隆重推出难过海绵
That's right, introducing Sad Sponge
最新款倒霉哥手办
The newest Bummer Dude action figure
踢一踢  扭一扭
And kick, and twist
踢一踢
and kick
踢高一点
Higher ladies
我说高一点
I said higher
让你见识什么叫高
I'll show you high
感受燃烧
Feel the burn
感受到了
I feel it
粉红色的护腿
Pink leg warmers?
对  怎么
Yeah, so?
这样
So
我爱死了
I love 'em
我们可是护腿兄弟
We're leg warmer buddies
拜托
Oh, please
我才不会戴着那顶帽子穿护腿
I wouldn't be caught dead in leg warmers with that hat
回时装学校补补课去吧
Go back to fashion school
他说得对
He's right
喂  时装学校吗
Hello, fashion school?
我要回去补课
I'm coming back
我重生了
I'm reborn
什么
What?
这包裹不是寄给我的
This package isn't even for me
裤头村 贝壳街124号
海绵宝宝收
是寄给海绵宝宝的
It's for SpongeBob
那邮递员简直笨死了
That mailman is a moron
吃东西时间到
And time for me to eat
而且
And
碗干干净净
Bowl is nice and clean
拿起小勺子
Grab my favorite spoon
拿衬衣擦一擦
Polish it on my shirt
牛奶
牛奶味道鲜
Milk is smelling fresh
麦片促活力
Cereal gives me pep
海草麦片圈
它自己在动
It's moving by itself
碗里闹鬼了
Ghosts are in my bowl
Ghosts are in my bowl?
碗里闹鬼了
Ghosts are in my bowl
我厨房闹鬼了
My kitchen's haunted
冷静  章鱼哥
Calm down, Squidward
你太累了  所以才会出幻觉
You're just seeing things because you're so tired
对对  就这样
Yeah, yeah, that's it
多睡一会就好了
You just need some more sleep
什么
What?
海跳蚤马戏团
我肯定还在做梦
I must still be dreaming
欢迎光临你的海跳蚤马戏团
Welcome to your Sea Flea Circus
为你提供娱乐是我们的义务
It's our duty to entertain you
太好看了
How delightful
太神了
Amazing
接下来干什么
What's next?
午餐时间
Lunchtime
Lunchtime?
做个梦还吃什么
Why would a dream need a--
我没做梦
This isn't a dream
是家里闹跳蚤了
It's an infestation
跳蚤哪去了
Where'd they go?
还不错
Not bad
我样子好帅
I look amazing
千万别咬我脸  把我美貌给毁了
Please don't ruin this by biting my face
你们毁了我美貌
You ruined it
面粉
为什么我会遭这种罪
Why is this happening to me?
啊对
Oh, yeah
都是报应
Karma
救命
Help
你们在
What are you--
感觉好暖和
That feels nice and warm
烘
焦
脆
煨
现在有点热了
It's actually getting kind of hot now
你们这是要把我烤了
You're trying to cook me
快放我出去
Let me out of here
欧洲萝卜
Parsnip?
你们疯了吗
Are you crazy?
我这种上等肉可不能配欧洲萝卜吃
You don't serve
a prime piece of meat like me with parsnip
应该要加柠檬提味
You need lemons to brighten my flavors
还要加胡椒或者香料
and some pepper or spice
好多了
Much better
快放我出去
Now let me out of here
这样做就对了
Now you're cookin'
不行  我纽扣脏了
Oh, no, my buttons are tarnished
马戏团跳蚤肯定不愿意
No circus flea is going to want
在纽扣脏的人面前表演
to perform for a guy with tarnished buttons
马戏团音乐
Circus music?
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
我来看一下
Just checking
你有没有看到过个寄给我的包裹
You've haven't seen a package addressed to me, have you?
我的马戏团跳蚤
My circus fleas
寄过来了
They came
盒子是空的
This box is empty
跳蚤哪去了
Where did the fleas go?
跳蚤们好
Hello, fleas
希望你帮忙喂过跳蚤了  章鱼哥
I hope you fed them, Squidward
它们会饿得慌
They can get pretty hungry
我已经喂过了
I fed them all right
赶紧取走吧
Please take them away now
没问题
You got it
把马戏团带到我家去吧
Now let's take this circus to my place
全体上车
All aboard
愿你每一天都能拥有海跳蚤马戏团
May all your days be Sea Flea Circus days
最美好的一天
Best day ever
笨蛋马戏团跳蚤
Stupid circus fleas
看看留下的这么一堆烂摊子
Just look at the mess they left
这是什么
What's this?
章鱼哥装病记
编剧
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
动画总监
联合监制
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
蟹堡王
干什么要那么久
What's taking so long?
我薯条都吃不到
I never got my fries
为什么我爸不爱我了
Why doesn't my father love me?
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
别闹
Quit it
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
别闹
Quit it
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
别闹
Quit it
章鱼哥先生  清理卫生间
Mr. Squidward, clean up in the head
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
还有清理这里
Also, clean up here
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
我说赶快清理
I said clean up
章鱼哥
Squidward
Hey, Squidward
章鱼哥
Squidward
Hey, Squidward
不
Oh, no
别光躺在那
Don't just lay there
去清理
Clean up
刚刚只是在做梦
It was just a dream
可怕又真实无比的梦
Just a horrible, realistic, totally on point dream
我居然会梦见我在上班
I can't believe I'm dreaming about work
明明还有不少有意思的事情可以做
when there's so many more
interesting things I could be doing
看看我没画完的画
Just look at my unfinished painting
没作完的交响曲
And my unfinished symphony
还有没吃的薄酥卷饼
And my uneaten strudel
我的薄酥卷饼
My strudel
味道跟普通馅饼一个样
Just tasted like pie to me
这可是薄酥卷饼  你个野蛮人
It's a strudel, you barbarian
你看上面油酥面皮这么多层
Just look at those pastry layers
没错
Oh, yeah
才刚醒来  一整天就已经乱套了
I just woke up and the day's already a disaster
我今天完全无法面对蟹堡王
I can't face the Krusty Krab today
我要待家里  潜入章鱼哥的美丽海洋
I am staying home and diving into an ocean of Squidward
夹心糖
怎么
What the--
那种多层馅饼还有吗
Any more of that layer pie?
出去
Get out
现在来除掉我身上另外的重担
Now to get rid of the other monkey on my back
蟹堡王
Krusty Krab
蟹老板  我是
Mr. Krabs, it's
章鱼哥
Squidward
章鱼哥先生
Mr. Squidward?
你在电话那头干什么
What are you doing on the phone?
你应该在上班的
You should be working
上不了
Can't work
我
Too
病重
sick
你声音听起来还挺不舒服
You do sound pretty bad
你确定你病重得上不了班吗
Are you sure you're too sick to work?
我是说  我是说
I mean, I mean
没错
positive
病重是吧
Too sick, eh?
我有办法可以治好你的病
I got the cure for what ails you
好好休息  章鱼哥先生
Well, you just rest up, Mr. Squidward
所有事情我都会照顾好的
I'll take care of everything
好  再见
Okay, bye
回头再说
talk to you--
我是说  我是说
I mean, I mean--
再见
Bye
没人能在蟹老板面前装病
No one fake sick on Mr. Krabs
还蒙混过关
and gets away with it
今天我不用上班
No work for me today
章鱼哥先生放心玩
Mr. Squidward gets to play
没客人可以恐惧
No customers for me to fear
海绵宝宝能沿着尖码头一路走下去
SpongeBob can take a long walk along a very sharp pier
一定是我点的蔬菜拼盘到了
That must be the crudité I ordered
好
Well--
蟹老板啊
Oh, Mr. Krabs
没看到你在
I didn't see you there
你好贴心
How thoughtful of you
能在我身体虚的时候来看我
to visit me in my weakened state
别放在心上  章鱼哥先生
Think nothing of it, Mr. Squidward
你打电话声音感觉特别不舒服
You sounded so bad on the phone
所以我就赶过来
I rushed right over
确保你把自己照顾好了
to make sure you were taking good care of yourself
我可不能把别人传染了
Well, I wouldn't want to infect anyone
你或许应该得走了
so you should probably go now
你现在可不适合自己一个人待家里
You are in no condition to be alone
所以我才给你带了帮手
That's why I brought you some help
让这位来治你  早上打电话找我
Take one of these and call me in the morning
医生来了
The doctor is in
用襁褓裹住
Swaddle, swaddle, swaddle
安静  别把自己拉伤了
Hush-aby now, don't strain yourself
说真的  蟹老板
Really, Mr. Krabs
这没多大必要
this isn't necessary
当然有必要了
Of course it is
要是让我发现你是在装病翘班
If I find out you were faking it just to get out of work
我就只能开除你了
I'd have to fire you
我没装病
No faking here
没  我真的
No, I'm really--
病了
sick
好  继续裹襁褓
Okay, back to the swaddling
好啊
Oh, yes
我喜欢
I like that
确实
Indeed
章鱼哥
Squidward
你劳累过度了
You're overexerting yourself
快让你身患重病的小小身体好好休息
Now you just rest that sick little body of yours
让我海绵宝宝来帮你画完你的自画像
while SpongeBob finishes up
your self-portrait for you
可
But--
很好  很好
Oh, yeah, oh, yeah
完成
Done
在我的想象中  你是个无助的小宝宝
In my imagination, you're a helpless little baby
你病情比我想的还要重
You're sicker than I thought
把那个黄色讨厌鬼忘了
Now just forget that yellow nuisance
让自己沉浸在音乐当中吧
and lose yourself in music
章鱼哥
Squidward
你身体这么虚  可不能浪费口气
You shouldn't be wasting your breath
in your weakened state
我来帮你吹竖笛
Let me blow the clarinet for you
不不  别碰我的
No, no, don't touch my--
别碰我的
Don't touch my--
完美的薄酥卷饼会让一切顺顺利利
The perfect strudel will make everything all right
章鱼哥
Oh, Squidward
该来测体温了
Time to take your temperature
快把那东西给我拿
Get that thing away from my--
37摄氏度
98.6度
98.6
章鱼哥  你已经好多了
Oh, Squidward, you're all better
我好高兴我们俩都能回蟹堡王去了
I'm so happy we can both go to the Krusty Krab now
什么
What?
不
No
把那东西给我
Give me that thing
你肯定是读数读错了
You must've read it wrong
那边有什么东西
What's that over there?
酷
Cool
一堵墙
A wall
好顺滑
So smooth
刚才真好玩
Well, that was fun
再来读一下体温计吧
Now, let's check that thermometer again, shall we?
拿去
Here you go
高烧
A fever
章鱼哥  必须把你冷却下来
Squidward, we got to cool you off
住手
Stop
说得对  还得更冷点
You're right, you need it even colder
谢谢
Thank you
天啊
Oh, boy
好了  舒服点没
There, all better?
没  你个傻蛋
N-no, you buffoon
你说得对  章鱼哥
You're right, Squidward
我一直都在
I have been
犯傻
buffoon
什么
W-w-what?
我之前一直都是治标不治本
I've been treating the symptoms
instead of the sickness
别拿那东西靠近我
Stay away from me with that thing
但是必须要知道你得的是什么病
But we have to figure out what you have
这样才能治
so we can treat it
不用了
No, uh
我已经知道我得的是什么病了
I already know what I have
是
It's, uh
急性
acute
疱疹
spotting
斯克罗博病
sclorboritis
急性疱疹斯克罗博病
Acute spotting sclorboritis?
从来没听过那种病
I never heard of that one
最好查一下
Better look it up
病情恶化了
You're getting worse
一定要赶快找到治疗方法
We've got to find a cure fast
找到了
I found it
就在这
Here it is
真的
You did?
对
Yup
治疗方法好像还挺简单
And the cure seems pretty simple
急性疱疹斯克罗博病
看见没
See?
等等
Wait--
等等  我有说急性斑点斯克罗博病吗
wait, did I say acute spotting sclorboritis?
不对  我肯定想说的是
No, no, I must've meant
普勒金顿综合征
plerkington's syndrome
找到了
Found it
来开始治疗吧
Now, let's get to the curing, shall we?
普勒金顿综合征
治好了吗
Are we done?
别傻了
Don't be silly
才刚开始
We've just begun
章鱼哥家
Tentacle's residence
我是海绵宝宝
SpongeBob speaking
喂  我的小子
Hello, me boy-o
病人怎么样了
How's the patient?
好多了
Better
我已经康复了
I'm all better
求你了  让我回去上班吧
Please, just let me go back to work
胡说八道
Nonsense
你看着还是病得不轻
You still look so sick
加大治疗力度  海绵宝宝
Better step up the cure, SpongeBob
就听你的  蟹老板
Whatever you say, Mr. Krabs
嘴巴张开
Open wide
你休想让那东西靠近我嘴巴
You will not get that anywhere near my mouth
你猜错了
Guess again
蟹堡王
于是根据书上的指示  我撑大他鼻子
So, the book told me to stretch his nose
用水母电他  然后把他肺部刮了一遍
shock him with a jellyfish, and then I scraped his lungs
再用一只食毒海胆把脏东西都清了
and cleaned them out with a toxic eating urchin
笑死我了
Priceless
怎么样  章鱼哥先生
Well, Mr. Squidward
生病几天过后感觉好点没
Feeling better after your sick day?
所言极是
You might say that
他好帅
He's glorious
没错  我从前有厌烦一切的毛病
That's right, I used to be sick of everything
但这毛病我再也没有了
but I'm not sick anymore
这工作多年来积累的毒素和压力
I've been plagued by toxins and stress
一直都在困扰着我
built up over the years at this job
但现在都让海绵宝宝给祛除了
but SpongeBob washed those away
此处点餐
现在谁想来点餐
Now, who wants to order?
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
肌肉
Muscles
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
我还要多层馅饼
More layered pie
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
不不不
No, no, no
我好像要得病了
I think I'm going to be sick